Hi, welcome to session twelve of learn and master guitar,
嗨，欢迎来到 learn and master guitar 第十二节课，
we're still working on learning and mastering this wonderful instrument,
我们仍在努力学习和掌握这一美妙的乐器，
this time, we're gonna talk about getting into some more advanced chords,
这一次，我们将谈论一些更高级的和弦，
two chords,
二和弦，
we're going to talk about minor eleventh chords,
我们将讨论小十一和弦，
talk about major seventh chords,
我们将谈论大七和弦，
chords that take you beyond what every other guitar player in the world is doing,
它们会让你超越世界上其他吉他演奏者正在做的事情，
because everybody knows the first batch of chords,
因为每个人都知道第一批和弦，
but now we're going to take you beyond that,
但现在我们将带你走出这一步，
to make your playing something special,
让你的演奏变得特别，
in the guitar tips section,
在吉他技巧部分，
we're going to talk about chord substitution,
我们将讨论和弦替换，
how you can look at a page
你如何看一页，
and even though it has C F and G
即使有 C F 和 G ，
just like every other piece of music,
就像其他音乐一样，
how you can grab some more different colors out of those chords
你如何从这些和弦中提取更多不同的音色，
to set your playing a part,
来设置你的弹奏部分，
going beyond what is written on the page
超越了页面上所写的内容，
to give you that great sound that you're looking for,
为你提供了正在寻找的美妙声音，
so let's go ahead and get started.
所以让我们继续前进，开始吧。
Okay, now we're going to talk about
好的，现在我们要讨论，
going beyond the regular batch of chords that everybody knows
不只是大家都知道的常规和弦，
and getting into a little bit more of some advanced chords,
而是一些更高级的和弦，
some chords that add some color and some depth and some richness to your playing,
一些和弦为你的演奏增添一些音色，一些深度和一些丰富的东西，
I learned some of these two chords
我学到了二和弦中的一些，
and I tell you I use them every time I play in a live situation or in a studio situation,
我告诉你，我每次在现场或录音室里演奏时都会用它们，
they just add that extra little bit of color,
它们只是增加了额外的一点音色，
that separates you from the guitar player sitting next to you,
把你和坐在你旁边的吉他手隔开，
that only knows C G and D.
只知道 C G 和 D 。
So here we go, let's talk about the first batch of chords,
好的，让我们来谈谈第一批和弦，
we're talking about two chords,
我们谈论二和弦，
what two chords are,
二和弦是什么，
a regular chord has,
一个常规的和弦有，
a regular major chord,
一个常规的大调和弦，
let's say a C major is using three different tones, a C E and G,
比如 C 大调使用三个不同的音调， C E G ，
and we'll explain why that is in a future session,
我们会在以后的课程中解释为什么会这样，
but for right now it's using three different notes C E and G,
但现在它使用了三个不同的音符， C E G ，
a two chord adds the second step of that major scale,
一个二和弦增加了大调音阶的第二步，
that D into that mix,
D 加入到混合中，
so now there's four tones messing around in there, C D E and G,
所以现在有四个音调在那里， C D E G ，
for a two chord,
对于二和弦，
so it just adds the second step of the scale into the triad of the chord
所以它只是将音阶的第二步加到和弦的三和弦中，
and that's what a two chord is,
这就是二和弦，
so we're going to very quickly go through some basic open, using open string two chords,
所以我们将很快地介绍一些基本的，使用开放琴弦的二和弦，
I'm going to cover a couple of movable versions for you,
我将为你们介绍几个变动的版本，
so you're going to cover these pretty quickly
所以你们将很快地学会这些，
and then we're going to do some exercises with them.
然后我们将用它们做一些练习。
Okay, first, we're going to cover is a C2,
好的，首先我们要介绍的是 C2 ，
that's one way to play it,
这是一种弹奏它的方式，
with your third finger, second and your pinky down here,
用你的无名指，中指和你的小拇指在这里，
another way to do it,
另一种弹奏方式，
which is a little more comfortable for me,
对我来说更舒服，
is to go two one and your third finger down here,
就是你的中指、食指和无名指在这里，
you can kind of hear, here's a C chord,
你可以听，这是一个 C 和弦，
adding that second step that D in there,
加上第二步 D ，
gives it just a little bit more color,
给它增加了一点音色，
that's a C2.
这是 C2 。
Next when we come to is a D2,
下一个我们要看的是 D2 ，
well, here's our D,
这是我们的 D ，
if I want a D2,
如果我想要 D2 ，
I just take that second finger off,
我就把中指拿开，
it's kind of an open sweet sound,
这是一种开放的甜美的声音，
that's a D2,
这是 D2 ，
a lot of times you'll hear a D going back and forth D2,
很多时候，你会听到一个 D 与 D2 切换，
real common thing,
很常见的事情，
that's where that D2 comes in.
这是 D2 的地方。
Next one we're going to cover is E2,
下一个我们要介绍的是 E2 ，
this one, here's a normal E,
这个是正常的 E ，
for an E2, we add the pinky out here,
对于 E2 ，我们在这里加上小拇指，
we gotta stretch out to that F#,
我们必须伸展到 F# ，
which is a little bit of a stretch,
这有点拉伸，
it might be difficult for your hand to do it the first time,
对你的手来说可能第一次很难做到，
but don't give up,
但不要放弃，
remember limberness your hand takes time,
记得[软化]你的手需要时间，
you may think, there's no way my pinky could stretch out there,
你可能会认为我的小拇指不可能延伸到那里，
actually your hand can stretch pretty wide,
你的手可以伸展得很宽，
if you need it to do so,
如果你需要的话，
and it just requires getting your hand a little bit more limber,
它只需要让你的手更灵活一点，
remember our finger exercise or stretching exercises,
记得我们的手指练习或伸展练习，
all these things will help that hand limber up,
所有这些都会帮助我的手向上伸展，
I used to could never get an E2,
我以前永远得不到 E2 ，
but once you do it a few times,
但一旦你做几次，
it gets more and more limber can do that,
它就会变得越来越灵活，可以做到，
here's an E, here's an E2,
这是 E ，这是 E2 ，
F# in there, that's what gives it that rich sound.
F# 在那里，这就是为什么它有丰富的声音。
Next one is a G2,
下一个是 G2 ，
here would be a G, and G2,
这里是 G ，和 G2 ，
I just dropped my second finger down to cover this A,
我使用我的无名指来按住 A ，
now you'll notice,
现在你会注意到，
that I had to take it off of this fifth string,
我得把第五弦拿出去，
well, what happens is that fifth string now,
好的，现在第五弦发生了什么，
my third finger is muting that string,
我的中指在使那根弦静音，
if if I went through it, just individual notes,
如果我使用它，是一个独立的音符，
you'd hear that dead string on that fifth string,
你会听到第五弦上的[死弦]，
I just, his little rear end is sitting on top of that string,
他的尾端在那根弦的顶端，
so in the heat of battle,
所以在[激烈的战斗]中，
when you play the whole chord,
当你弹奏整个和弦时，
you don't hear that dead string,
你听不到那根死弦，
but it's in there,
但它就在那里，
it's just covered up by the others,
它被其他弦掩盖了，
that's a G2.
这是 G2 。
Next one is an A2,
下一个是 A2 ，
here's A,
这是 A ，
A2, I just take that pinky off,
A2 ，我只是把那个小拇指拿开，
it's a real open sound.
这是一个真正开放的声音。
Going through those again,
再过一遍，
C2, D2, E2, G2 and A2.
C2 D2 E2 G2 和 A2 。
Now those may be coming pretty fast by you right now,
这些形式可能很快就会出现，
as you practice them a little bit,
当你练习它们的时候，
you those will get more and more underneath your fingers,
它们会越来越多地在你的手指下面，
now let's talk about,
现在让我们来讨论，
those are the open forms, that you use most often.
这些是开放形式，你常使用的。
Now here we're going to talk about the movable forms,
现在我们将讨论可移动形式，
once you get a couple of movable forms in you,
一旦你得到几个可移动形式，
remember you can play that anywhere on the neck in any key,
记住你可以在琴颈上用任何调弹奏，
so I'm going to give you an F2, and a B2,
所以我会给你一个 F2 和一个 B2 ，
I may even sneak in a G2 in there too,
我甚至也可以在里面加一个 G2 ，
a six string form of it,
一个六根弦的形式，
so you can play anywhere on the neck.
所以你可以在琴颈上的任何地方弹奏。
Okay, so we're gonna start on F2 first,
好的，我们首先从 F2 开始，
this one is based on the third fret,
这个是基于第三品，
you're borrowing this first finger all the way down,
你把食指横按，
you have a C here, an F here and a G underneath,
这里有一个 C ，这里有一个 F ，以及一个 G ，
that's a four string chord,
这是一个四根弦的和弦，
where's the F in this F2,
这个 F2 中的 F 在哪里，
right here on our first finger right there,
就在这里，在我们的食指上，
that's the note you're pivoting off of,
这是你要[旋转]的音符，
so if I want to,
所以如果我想，
let's say, make that F#2,
比如 F#2 ，
I move this up to an F#
我把这个调到 F# ，
and I go from there,
我就得到了，
if I want an Ab,
如果我想要 Ab ，
it would be like that.
它会是这样的。
So I have F2,
所以我有 F2 ，
now if you want to think of it this way,
如果你想这样想，
if I keep going down, E2, Eb2,
如果我继续降， E2 Eb2 ，
if I went down one more,
如果我再降一品，
then I run off my neck,
我就会跑出我的琴颈，
but look there's my D2,
但看这是我的 D2 ，
so it's really the same form,
所以这是类似的形式，
I just barre it, to make where,
我可以横按来，
I could make it in different places on the neck,
我可以在琴颈上的不同地方做出它，
that's F2, that's a four string version of it.
这是 F2 ，这是四根弦的版本。
If I wanted to use something on the fifth string,
如果我想用五弦上的东西，
let's do a Bb2 or a B2,
让我们做 Bb2 或 B2 ，
let's do a B2, keep it consistent,
让我们做一个 B2 ，保持一致，
it's kind of like our Bm, Bm that we had,
这有点像我们的 Bm ，
I take my second finger off,
我把我的食指拿开，
make sure that barres down nice and strong,
确保横按好而有力，
and I get a B2
我得到了 B2 ，
and again where's the B,
再一次， B 在哪里，
where's the pivot note,
枢轴音符在哪里，
right where that diamond is at on that fifth string,
在第五弦上钻石符号这里，
so if I want to D2,
所以如果我想要 D2 ，
in that barre form,
在横按形式中，
let's make it an Eb2 that way,
让我们做一个 Eb2 ，
doesn't get confused with the other,
不要和另一个混淆，
I come up here to Eb, there's my Eb
我来到这里 Eb ，这是 Eb ，
and there's my two chord.
这是我的二和弦。
Okay, so I've got a four string version,
好的，所以我有四根弦的版本，
I've got a fifth string version.
我有五根弦的版本。
Now the only low version I know is
现在，我所知道的唯一低音版本是，
kind of a growl kind of sound,
一种咆哮的声音，
that I use sometimes,
我有时会用到。
Let's see, if I want a G2, in a barre version,
让我们来看看，如果我想要一个 G2 ，横按版本，
I just do this one,
我做这个，
a little bit of a stretch,
做了一点拉伸，
especially to get that second and third finger separated away from each other,
特别是为了让中指和无名指彼此分开，
and I just do the first of, the bottom four strings,
我只做了底部的四根弦，
remember movable chords,
记住可移动的和弦，
don't use any open strings,
不要使用任何开放的弦，
that's a secret,
这是一个秘诀，
where's the G in this G2,
这个 G2 里的 G 在哪里，
right there,
就在这里，
if I want a B2, be right there,
如果我想要 B2 ，就在这里，
or A2,
或者 A2 ，
I use this chord sometimes,
我有时会用这个和弦，
if I want to get to a real open sound,
如果我想听到真正的开放式声音，
it's a very distinctive kind of an open sound
这是一种非常独特的开放式声音，
using all those fifths and fourths.
使用了所有五弦和四弦。
Those are some two chords,
这是一些二和弦，
now we covered what six or seven forms there,
我们讨论了六种或七种形式，
those are the main batch that I use,
这是我主要使用的一批，
okay, I got moveable ones,
好的，我有可移动的，
I can play in any key,
我可以用任何调演奏，
I've got three different types I choose removable ones,
我有三种不同的类型，我选择可移动的，
I've got my open ones down here,
我在下面有我的开放的，
if I want to get that sweet open string ringing sound,
如果我想得到甜美的开放的弦声，
let's talk about the next batch major seventh chords.
让我们来谈谈下一批，大七和弦。
Okay, major seventh chords,
好的，大七和弦，
we're gonna run through about six or seven of these.
我们将介绍大约六到七个。
A Cmaj7, open version,
Cmaj7 开放版本，
here's my C,
这是我的 C ，
take my first finger off,
把我的食指拿开，
I have a good Cmaj7,
我有一个好的 Cmaj7 ，
very common progression,
非常常见的进程，
using that open Cmaj7.
使用开放的 Cmaj7 。
Next one is a Dmaj7,
下一个是 Dmaj7 ，
this one is a little bit different,
这个有点不同，
there's our D,
这是我们的 D ，
but I have to switch my fingers around on this,
但我必须交换我的手指，
when I use my second finger and my third finger to get this,
用我的中指和无名指来得到这个，
Dmaj7, actually that was the Dmaj9,
Dmaj7 ，实际上那是 Dmaj9 ，
let me show you this one,
让我向你们展示这个，
Dmaj7 would be this way,
Dmaj7 是这样的，
barring that first finger on that second fret, all the way down,
食指横按在第二品，就完成了，
Dmaj7, D, Dmaj7.
Dmaj7 ， D Dmaj7 。
Okay, next, let's go to an Fmaj7,
好的，接下来是 Fmaj7 ，
here would be an F,
这是 F ，
bottom half of it would be like this,
下半部分像这样，
if I want an Fmaj7,
如果我想要 Fmaj7 ，
I just come up on this,
我就用这个，
so I have an F and A a C
所以我有一个 F 和 A C ，
and then this open E string right there,
然后这里有一个开放的 E 弦，
Fmaj7.
Fmaj7 。
Let's do a Gmaj7,
让我们做 Gmaj7 ，
or you could do it that way too,
或者你也可以这样做，
let's teach you that way,
让我这样教你，
again I have my dead string right here,
再次，死弦在这里，
and first finger down here on this F#.
食指在这个 F# 上。
Now these don't sound too interesting,
现在这些听起来不太有趣，
when you just kind of plan in a row like that,
当你只是把它们放在一起的时候，
when you combine them with other chord changes,
当你把它们和其他和弦改变放在一起时，
that's where the color starts to come in.
这就是音色开始出现的地方。
Next one is a Amaj7,
下一个是 Amaj7 ，
here's A,
这是 A ，
if I switch my fingers around a little bit,
如果我交换一下手指，
I get an Amaj7,
我得到 Amaj7 ，
second finger, first finger, third finger and then open,
中指，食指，无名指，然后空弦，
Amaj7.
Amaj7 。
Those are the basic major seventh open chords,
这些是基本的开放大七开弦，
Cmaj7, Dmaj7, Fmaj7, Gmaj7, and Amaj7.
Cmaj7 Dmaj7 Fmaj7 Gmaj7 和 Amaj7 。
Okay, now the move, as far as the movable forms,
好的，可移动的形式，
well what can we do,
我们可以做什么，
well, here's the two that I use the most,
这是我使用最多的两个，
if I'm basing it off of the fifth string,
如果我是以第五弦为基础的话，
it would be a Bb
它是 Bb ，
or let's do it, let's do it Bb,
或者我们来做 Bb ，
it's kind of a Bb7 would be,
这像 Bb7 ，
but I put my second finger down here on the second fret on the third string,
但我把食指放在第三弦上的第二品上，
and I get a Bbmaj7,
我得到 Bbmaj7 ，
where's the Bb in this Bbmaj7,
Bbmaj7 中的 Bb 在哪里，
right here on that first fret, second, fifth string,
就在这里，第五弦的第一品，
this is where the Bb is.
这就是 Bb 的地方。
So if I wanted an Ebmaj7,
所以如果我想要 Ebmaj7 ，
I'd have to come up, do something like that.
我就到这里，做这样的事情。
Okay, next one on the sixth string is going to Fmaj7
好的，下一个第六弦上的是 Fmaj7 ，
and that's this one,
它是这个，
again, I'm muting out that fifth string,
再次，我要静音第五弦，
no barre in this one
这个没有横按，
and I just play the five strings,
我只弹奏五根弦，
I don't play this last string,
我不弹奏最后一根弦，
because that would be an open string
因为那是一根空弦，
and then it wouldn't work,
它不起作用，
so if I want an Abmaj7,
所以如果我想要 Abmaj7 ，
I just move this up to Ab,
我只需要把这个移到 Ab ，
there's Ab,
这是 Ab ，
what about a Dbmaj7,
那么 Dbmaj7 呢，
no problem, I don't need my Mel Bay's chord bible for this,
我不需要我的 Mel Bay 的和弦圣经来做这个，
I just know three forms
我只知道三种形式，
and I know where to put them in different places,
我知道把它们放在不同的地方，
I don't need to go through 50 million different permutations of it,
我不需要经历 5000 万个不同的排列，
in order to come up with an Fmaj7 or a Dbmaj7,
为了得出 Fmaj7 或 Dbmaj7 ，
I'm a guitar player,
我是一个吉他手，
I went the easy way,
我使用简单的方法，
so I only know three of them,
我只知道其中的三个，
and you just put it in the place that you need to use that.
你只要把它放在你需要用的地方。
Okay, here's one on the fourth string,
好的，这是第四弦上的，
let's say I wanted to do an Ebmaj7,
假设我想做 Ebmaj7 ，
I do this, I barre these three,
我做这个，横按这三个，
remember how our Dmaj7 was like this,
记得我们的 Dmaj7 像这样，
I screwed it up and make a barre out of it,
我把它搞砸了，做了一个横按，
Ebmaj7
Ebmaj7 ，
and then I've got one on the fourth string,
然后我得到一个四弦的，
I've got a version on the fifth string,
我有一个五弦的版本，
I got a version on the six string,
我有一个六弦的版本，
I can play Ebmaj7 -} all over the neck all day long,
我可以整天在琴颈上弹奏 Ebmaj7 ，
that's where the beauty of these movable chords comes into.
这就是这些可移动和弦的美丽之处。
Okay, the last batch, okay, is minor eleventh chords,
好的，最后一批是小十一和弦，
we've covered what about fifteen chords so far,
到目前为止，我们已经讲过了 15 个和弦怎么样，
I've got a couple more I'm gonna lay on you here,
我还有几个和弦，列在这里，
there's only two, that I really use for open minor eleventh chords,
这里我只用两个，开放小十一和弦，
don't worry about the eleventh chord,
不要担心十一和弦，
all that is is I'm adding the fourth step of the scale,
所有就是我加入了第四步的音阶，
which is the eleventh,
也是是第十一，
it just repeats,
它只是重复，
if I keep going up the major scale,
如果我继续提高大调音阶，
one two three four five six seven eight,
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 ，
I hit the octave 9 11,
我到了八度 9 11 ，
it goes up to actually the fourth degree of the scale,
它实际上上升到了第四步音阶，
which is the same as the eleventh degree,
这与第十一级相同，
which is the same as the fourth,
也就是第四级，
don't get too lost in that,
不要迷失了，
we'll learn more about that later.
我们稍后会了解更多。
But we're going to start off with an open F#m11,
但我们将从 F#m11 开始，
again, I'm muting this fifth string,
再次，我把第五根弦调成静音，
so I don't want to put it so up to that fifth string comes through,
所以我不想把它放到第五根弦上，
I don't want that,
我不想这样，
I want to mute it out
我想把它静音，
and I have these two open,
我有这两个空弦，
pinky on the A, third finger on the E,
小拇指在 A 上，无名指在 E 上，
second finger I like to use up here on the F#,
中指在 F# 上，
okay, that works great for open minor eleventh chord,
好的，这在开放小十一和弦上起作用，
if I want one off the fifth string,
如果我想要第五弦上的一根，
it would be like a Bm11,
它就像 Bm11 ，
okay, here I could mute,
好的，这里我可以静音，
if I want to or not mute that in a string,
如果我想或不想静音，
that's a Bm11,
这是 Bm11 ，
F#m11, Bm11.
F#m11 Bm11 。
Now if I'm going a little fast for you,
现在如果我讲得有点快，
just put it on pause,
把它停下来，
get these chord forms underneath your belt
把这些和弦形式掌握，
and then come back to me.
然后回来找我。
Okay.
好的。
Let's talk about some movable ones,
我们来谈谈一些可移动的，
if I want to move this,
如果我想移动这个，
here's that F#m11,
这是 F#m11 ，
well if I just move it up a half step
如果我把它上移半音，
and put my first finger down here,
把我的食指放在这里，
don't use that last six string or last first string here,
不要用最后第六根弦或最后第一根弦，
I just hit these five,
我只弹了这五根，
I get a Gm11
我得到了 Gm11 ，
and again that one doesn't have any open strings,
再次，那个没有任何空弦，
so yeah, I can move that anywhere I want,
所以我可以把它移到我想要的任何地方，
Bbm11, no problem,
Bbm11 ，没问题，
move it up to Bb, make my chord here.
把它移动到 Bb ，得到我的和弦。
Okay, if I wanted one that's based off of the fifth string,
好的，如果我想要一个基于第五弦的，
well, here's my Bm11 remember,
好的，这是我的 Bm11 ，
well if I screwed him up a half step
如果我把它上升半音，
and kind of barre this over here,
在这里横按，
again that may be a little bit of a stretch,
再次，这可能有点伸展，
that's a Cm11,
这是 Cm11 ，
here's the C in that Cm11.
这是 Cm11 中的 C 。
But Steve, I need an Fm11,
但是 Steve ，我需要 Fm11 ，
hey, no problem,
嘿，没问题，
I screwed up to F
我上升到 F ，
and I make the minor eleventh there.
在那里得到小十一和弦。
See how that works,
看到它是如何工作的，
I don't need to look at my chord bible to find it,
我不需要看我的和弦圣经来找到它，
I only know a couple of forms,
我只知道几种形式，
I know where to move them in different spots,
我知道把它们移到不同的地方，
that's what that comes down to.
这就是为什么。
After this, we're gonna go into some exercises
在这之后，我们将进行一些练习，
and work on these chord forms that we just learned.
并处理我们刚刚学到的这些和弦形式。
Okay, now we're going to talk about some guitar tips
好的，现在我们将讨论一些吉他技巧，
on how to use these chords that we've learned,
关于如何使用这些我们学到的和弦，
you've got a whole new batch of chords underneath your belt,
你已经掌握了一批新的和弦，
now it's not all that many,
现在它不是那么多了，
I mean, we've learned the basic chords, which that was what about twenty chords,
我的意思是，我们已经学习了基本的和弦，那就是 20 个和弦，
I've just taught you about another twenty chords,
我刚刚教了你另外 20 个和弦，
so now it's really only about forty chords, we know,
所以现在只知道 40 个和弦，
which sounds huge,
这听起来很多，
but once you play him a lot,
但一旦你经常给弹奏它，
he gets to be just like the alphabet,
它就会变得就像字母表一样，
I mean just you can go through in any key
我的意思是，你可以用任何调通过，
and these chords separate the men from the boys
这些和弦区分男人和男孩，
on playing harmonies and making creative chord progressions,
在弹奏和声和创造性和弦进程中，
you ever listen to a song
你听过一首歌，
and you think gosh it just sounds so rich what he's playing,
你会想，天哪，他演奏的听起来太丰富了，
a lot of what he's doing,
很多他所做的，
it's just some simple tricks
只是一些简单的技巧，
of which here's one of the main ones, chord substitution.
这里是主要技巧之一，和弦替换。
Okay, when I look at a piece of paper,
好的，当我看着一张纸，
they put out, they put a piece of music for me on a studio session
他们在录音室会议上为我放了一段音乐，
and they say, okay, well, here's the chords,
他们说，好的，这是和弦，
it goes from a C to a G,
从 C 开始到 G ，
okay, I don't play a C and a G,
好的，我不弹奏 C 和 G ，
because every other [] going to play a C and a G,
因为其他[]都会弹奏 C 和 G ，
just like this,
就像这样，
I substitute a two chord for both of those,
我用两个二和弦来替换这两个，
here's the rule,
这是规则，
you can substitute a two chord for any major chord,
你可以用二和弦来替换任何大调和弦，
so if it's a C, it's an F,
所以如果它是 C F ，
if it's a Bb, Gb, Ab,
如果它是 Bb Gb Ab ，
doesn't matter,
无关紧要，
you can substitute a two chord for that
你可以使用二和弦替换它，
and it's going to sound rich and full,
它会听起来丰富和饱满，
it works a hundred percent of the time.
它百分之百的工作。
Okay, so if it's if it's going from a C to a G,
好的，如果它是从 C 到 G ，
let's say the chord progression is that,
假设和弦进程是这样，
okay, well, I don't, I don't play that,
好的，我不弹奏这个，
I play a C2 to maybe a G2,
我可能弹奏 C2 到 G2 ，
it just gives it a little bit more color,
它只是给它增加了一点音色，
a little bit more depth to what we're playing,
一点深度，给我们弹奏的东西，
that's the first rule, two chords,
这是第一条规则，二和弦，
what's the rule,
规则是什么，
you can add a two chord to any major chord,
你可以在任何大调和弦上加上二和弦，
the chord says D,
和弦比如是 D ，
I don't play a D,
我不弹 D ，
I hardly ever play a D,
我几乎从来不弹 D ，
I play a D2,
我弹 D2 ，
it says G,
它说 G ，
I don't play G, I play G2,
我不弹奏 G ，我弹奏 G2 ，
well, isn't that going to screw up the rest of the band, nope,
这不会搞砸乐队的其他人吗，不会，
I can pretty much say,
我几乎可以说，
for these two chords,
对于这些二和弦，
you can it's never going to screw up the rest of the band,
你可以，它永远不会搞砸乐队的其他部分，
because you're just adding a little bit of color into the mix,
因为你只是在混合中添加了一点音色，
so you're not changing the harmony or anything like that,
所以你没有改变和声或任何类似的东西，
you're adding a little bit of color.
你添加了一些音色。
Talk about the second one,
说说第二个，
the second one is a minor eleventh,
第二个是小十一和弦，
well, what can I do,
好的，我能做什么，
if it's a minor chord,
如果是小调和弦，
I can substitute a minor eleventh for it,
我可以用小十一和弦来替换它，
and almost all the time,
并且几乎所有时间，
you'll never have a problem with it,
你永远不会有问题，
that one I have to have a little bit more of a clarification on it,
除非我对它有更多的澄清，
with the minor eleventh,
对于小十一和弦，
they work almost all the time,
它们几乎一直工作，
so any when I see a minor chord,
所以当我看到一个小调和弦时，
I can substitute in a minor eleventh
我可以使用小十一和弦替换，
and it's not going to throw anybody off.
这不会让任何人失望。
Okay, so those are the two rules,
好的，所以这是两个规则，
two chords for major,
二和弦对于大调，
eleventh minor eleventh chords for minor.
小十一和弦对于小调。
Here's your assignment for this week,
这是本周的作业，
I want you to practice all of the advanced chord forms, that we've just learned,
我希望你们练习我们刚刚学到的所有高级和弦形式，
get them underneath your fingers,
让它们在你的手指下，
be able to play in different parts of the neck,
能够在琴颈的不同部分弹奏，
be able to play them enough to where you're not hesitating when you get to them
当你达到它们时，你能够毫不犹豫地弹奏它们，
and you can form them in one block, not note note note,
你可以在一个区块中形成它们，而不是音符、音符、音符，
you know sometimes when you're going for a chord
有时当你要找一个和弦，
and as you're just learning it,
当你刚刚学习它的时候，
you kind of start off with,
你可以这样开始，
well here's my first finger there,
这是我的第一个手指，
next one you kind of build it in, blah, in in a sequence
下一个你可以把按顺序，
of putting your fingers down,
把手指放下来，
you want to get these chords down enough to where you come as a block.
你想把这些和弦当成一个区块。
Okay, practice all your advanced chord forms,
好的，练习你所有的高级和弦形式，
play through the chord substitution exercises in your book,
通过你书中的和弦替换练习，
there's also gonna be exercises
也有练习，
getting your fingers familiar with these various advanced chord forms too,
让你的手指熟悉这些不同的高级和弦形式，
also remember the Jam Along CDs,
也记得 Jam Along CD ，
you can always get more resources off of that,
你总是可以从中获得更多的资源，
as well as there's extra resources in your book as well,
而且你的书中也有额外的资源，
so let's go ahead and work out at the workshop
所以我们继续，在 workshop 上，
and I'll see you there.
我们在那里见。
Okay, now let's put,
好的，现在让我们，
in our workshop time,
在我们的 workshop 时间里，
all these chord substitutions that we've learned
把我们学到的所有这些和弦替换
and the new chords into a working environment,
和新的和弦放到一个工作环境中，
where you can start getting the most out of it.
在那里你可以最大限度地利用它。
Okay, so look at your a chord exercises page,
所以看你的和弦练习页面，
okay, we're going to do number one,
好的，我们要做第一个，
we'll start off pretty slow
我们会非常缓慢地开始，
and then we'll speed it up,
然后我们会加快速度，
give you a chance to get these chords underneath your belt.
给你机会来掌握这些和弦。
Okay, number one, starts out with two chord exercises,
好的，第一个，从二和弦练习开始，
ready, starts on a C2, go,
准备，从 C2 开始，
Am7,
Am7 ，
D2,
D2 ，
G2,
G2 ，
just running you through these chords,
只需弹奏这些和弦，
then C.
然后 C 。
Do it again, a little bit faster,
再做一次，速度更快一点，
let me try that,
让我试一试，
let me see if I can get right,
让我看看我是否能弹好，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Okay, look at the second one,
好的，看第二个，
that starts out on an E2,
从 E2 开始，
ready, get that form right,
准备，准备好形式，
get that pinky stretching all the way out there,
让小指一直伸展到那里，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
A2,
A2 ，
back to E2,
回到 E2 ，
A2.
A2 。
Now, I'm not very, I'm not giving you very complex on your rhythm,
现在，我不会给你非常复杂的节奏，
because I really wanted you to focus on forming these chords.
因为我想让你专注于形成这些和弦。
Okay, number three, get a little work on these open chords
好的，第三个，在这些开放和弦上做一些工作，
and some of the movable ones,
一些可移动的，
F2, starts it out,
从 F2 开始，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
Gm7,
Gm7 ，
Bb2 is next,
下一个是 Bb2 ，
Csus,,
Csus ，
C7.
C7 。
Let's do it again,
让我们再来一遍，
F2
F2 ，
Gm7
Gm7 ，
try get all those notes to ring out, no buzzes,
试着让所有音符发声，没有嗡嗡声，
Csus,
Csus ，
C7,
C7 ，
F2.
F2 。
Great, okay, now let's take a look at some of the major seventh forms that we've learned,
好的，现在让我们来看一些学过的大七和弦形式，
remember, Cmaj7, Fmaj7, Dmaj7, Amaj7, okay, Gmaj7,
记得吗， Cmaj7 Fmaj7 Dmaj7 Amaj7 Gmaj7 ，
the movable ones, Fmaj7, Bbmaj7 and Ebmaj7.
可移动的， Fmaj7 Bbmaj7 Ebmaj7 ，
okay, so what is that about eight forms.
好的，也就是八种形式。
Get little practice on that,
做一些练习，
starting with number one, major seventh chord exercises number one,
从第一个开始，大七和弦练习一，
you ready, starts on that Cmaj7
你准备好了吗，从 Cmaj7 开始，
and I gave a little rhythm there,
我给出一点节奏，
down, down up, up, down,
下，下上，上，下，
here we go, one two, nice and slow, go,
让我们开始， 1 2 ，慢一点，开始，
Dm7,
Dm7 ，
Fmaj7,
Fmaj7 ，
Gsus, I gotta do a barre form,
Gsus ，我做一个横按形式，
Cmaj7,
Cmaj7 ，
Okay, now let's try and do the next one,
好的，现在让我们试着做下一个，
starts on a Dmaj7,
从 Dmaj7 开始，
okay, now look at that rhythm,
好的，现在看看节奏，
down, up, keep that hand going, down, up,
下，上，保持你的手移动，下，上，
okay, two, ready, play,
好的， 2 ，准备，弹奏，
Em7,
Em7 ，
Asus,
Asus ，
Gmaj7,
Gmaj7 ，
Dmaj7
Dmaj7 。
Do it again, little bit faster,
再做一次，快一点，
Em7,
Em7 ，
Asus,
Asus ，
Gmaj7,
Gmaj7 ，
Dmaj7.
Dmaj7 。
Great, gives you a little practice with those,
好的，给了你一点练习，
now let's go on to minor elevens,
现在让我们继续小十一和弦，
okay, starts out with an E2
好的，从 E2 开始，
and it goes on to there that F#m11,
它继续到 F#m11 ，
look at that rhythm too,
也看看那个节奏，
let's start it nice and slow,
让我们慢慢开始，
one, two, ready go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
down, down up, keep your hand going,
下，下上，保持你的手移动，
Bm11,
Bm11 ，
E7,
E7 ，
Amaj7.
Amaj7 ，
Do it one more time, little faster,
再来一次，快一点，
A2, Bm11, E7, Amaj7.
A2 Bm11 E7 Amaj7 。
Number two, we end up with, start off with a Gm11,
第二个，我们以 Gm11 开始，
a little bit of a movable chord there,
这里有一点可移动的和弦，
take a look at that rhythm too,
也看看那个节奏，
one two, ready, go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
rest,
休息，
D7,
D7 ，
back to that Gm11,
回到 Gm11 ，
Dsus,
Dsus ，
Gm11.
Gm11 。
Great, now let's start looking at some of the chords substitution examples there,
很好，现在让我们开始看一些和弦替换的例子，
the first one there goes through a basic, very basic four chord progression,
第一个例子是一个基本的四和弦进程，
C Am Dm and G,
C Am Dm G ，
now if I just play it normally,
现在，如果我正常演奏，
it sounds like this,
它听起来是这样的，
okay, now if I substitute to use my chord substitution rules,
好的，现在如果我用我的和弦替换规则，
what are the two rules,
两条规则是什么，
if it's a major chord, I can substitute a two chord in for it,
如果是大调和弦，我可以用二和弦替换，
if it's a minor chord I can substitute a minor eleventh,
如果是小调和弦，我可以用小十一和弦替换，
so I'm gonna change that C to a C2,
所以我要改变那个 C 为 C2 ，
I'm going to change that Am to an Am11,
我要把 Am 改为 Am11 ，
I'm going to change that Dm to a Dm11,
我要把 Dm 改成 Dm11 ，
I'm gonna change that G to a G2,
我要把 G 改成 G2 ，
see how that changes the color.
看看音色是怎么改变的。
One two, ready go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
do it again,
再来一次，
did you hear how drastically it changed the color
你有没有听到它有多么剧烈地改变了音色，
and made it so much more rich
使它变得更加丰富，
and totally harmonically interesting to listen to.
听起来非常有趣。
Look at that second example there,
看看第二个例子，
starts off with an A,
以 A 开头，
then goes to an E, F#m and then D,
然后转到 E F#m D ，
if I played it normally,
如果我正常弹奏，
it would sound like this,
它听起来是这样的，
sounds pretty plain,
听起来很平淡，
let's throw in our chord substitutions,
让我们加上和弦替换，
I turn the A into an A2,
我把 A 变成 A2 ，
the E to an E2,
E 变成 E2 ，
the F#m to an F#m11,
F#m 变成 F#m11 ，
the D to a D2
D 变成 D2 ，
and see if it does sound a little more colorful to you,
看看它是否听起来更有音色，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
let's play again, do it again,
我们再弹一次，
you hear how much more interesting that becomes to your ear,
你会听到这对你的耳朵来说变得多么有趣，
and that's what separates some players
这就是一些演奏者的不同之处，
and then gives them that distinctive sound
然后给它们独特的声音，
is learning these two chords, learning these major sevenths, learning these minor eleventh
就是学习二和弦，学习大七和弦，学习小十一和弦，
and applying a little bit of chord substitution rules to them,
并对它们应用一点替换规则，
there's other chord substitution rules as well,
还有其他和弦替换规则，
but these two I found have been the most bang for the buck
但我发现这两个规则是最划算的，
in learning and getting underneath your fingers.
在学习和掌握你的手指上。
So I would encourage you to keep on,
所以我鼓励你继续，
trying keep on wrestling with it,
继续与之搏斗，
don't give up,
不要放弃，
you've come this far,
你已经走了这么远，
you can certainly get beyond this
你肯定可以超越这一点，
and turn into the guitar player that you were meant to be.
成为你注定要成为的吉他手。
we'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。